Sourabh Deshmukh

Kolhapur, MH • sourabh.deshmukh.988@gmail.com • +919890943898 • https://sourabhdeshmukh.in

OBJECTIVE

A Dynamic DevOps Engineer having 3+ years of experience, looking for a platform where I can implement my skills which I have learned with my past experience and can get a chance to gain new skills which will help me to grow in future professionally and personally.

EDUCATION

K.E.S. Rajarambapu Institute of Technology, Rajaramnagar.

Shivaji University, Kolhapur.

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science and Engineering. CGPA: 7.51/10.0

May 2019

WORK EXPERIENCE

Opcito Technologies Pvt. Ltd.

Pune, Maharashtra.

DevOps Engineer

Aug, 2021 – Present

- Configured and set up CICD pipelines using Jenkins to package, test Android and IOS applications. Published them on Drobox and Atlassian Confluence page.
- Set up CircleCI pipelines with git and wrote helm charts to deploy application components with kubernetes and Rancher on GKE cluster.
- Assisted with terraform code for configuration and deployment of AWS WAF rules.

kPoint Technologies Pvt. Ltd.

Pune, Maharashtra.

Software Engineer | DevOps

Oct, 2019 - Aug, 2021

- Structured CICD end-to-end pipelines using Jenkins to build test and deploy application to QA/Staging/Prod.
- Dockerized product application components to reduce dependency issues. Optimized docker images with multi stag builds and reducing layers in image.
- Managed several system components order using automation scripts (Python & Shell) and tools.
- Reduced cost of AWS resources by converting on-demand resources to spot using terraform.
- Centralized system and application logging using ELK stack. Designed Monitoring dashboards using Kibana.

Software Engineer Intern | DevOps

Jan, 2019 – Sept, 2019

- Implemented staging setup of kPoint web application and Deployed on AWS cloud.
- The infrastructure was managed using terraform, server and application configuration was managed using Puppet and python scripts, Deployment was done using Jenkins CICD pipeline.
- Production Servers and application monitoring using Nagios Server and Munin Monitoring. Deployed monitoring scripts on production servers to maintain 24/7 availability of application and reduced downtime.
- Configured AWS Guard duty and AWS WAF to secure the production cloud from external attacks.

CloudYuga Technologies Pvt. Ltd.

Bangalore, Karnataka.

Software Engineer Intern

Summer 2018

- Built a web application from scratch using NodeJS, Docker, Docker Compose and Markdown.
- The primary focus of the building application was to reduce individual configuration task at kubernetes classroom training.

SOCIAL EXPOSURE

- Volunteered for Organizing Committee at PyCon India 2019 Chennai.
- RootConf 2019 Bangalore.
- DevConf 2018 Bangalore.
- NullCon International Security Conference 2018 Goa.
- Open Source India Conference 2017 Bangalore.

CERTIFICATIONS

- Red Hat Certified Engineer (RHEL 7).
- Red Hat Certified System Administrator (RHEL 7).
- Cisco Certified Network Associate (Routing & Switching).

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Skills & Interests: DevOps, Cloud Platforms (AWS, GCP), Virtualization (K8S, Docker). Automation Tools (Ansible, Puppet, Terraform, Helm). CICD (Jenkins, Circle CI), Monitoring (ELK, Nagios, Munin), Databases (MySQL, Redis).